<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on Hugo on Mika Aguilar</title>
    <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on Hugo on Mika Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Layouts</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-3/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need some templates to render your new content. Hugo templates exist in the /layouts directory. The docs for the base templates are decent, but I&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick rundown from top to bottom.
Baseof At the very top of your site is the layouts/default/baseof.html. This includes the outer shell of your site starting from the &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; element. Here is a minimal example I pulled from the docs:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19  &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Setup, Directories, and Content</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-2/</guid>
      <description>This guide assumes that you aren&amp;rsquo;t going to read any of the Hugo docs. I&amp;rsquo;m totally ok with that - I&amp;rsquo;ll link you to the parts that I&amp;rsquo;d otherwise repeat. We&amp;rsquo;ll also be sticking with the bare minimum needed to get going with a blog and have a great time. There are plenty of bells and whistles I&amp;rsquo;ll show you in a later section of the guide.
Step 0 - Installing Hugo The very first thing you need to do is install the binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Why Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/posts/blogging-on-hugo/part-1/</guid>
      <description>This site is running Hugo with GitHub pages, and I am really happy with the setup. There are a lot of options for spinning up a personal blog site, and I really think building with Hugo is the best option. I&amp;rsquo;m going to guide you through building a blog in this series of posts. Lets start off with the most important question - why.
The JAMStack 🎸 Hugo is a static site generator, which is the Markdown bit of the JAMStack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>