<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mika Aguilar</title>
    <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mika Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupled Drupal with Gatsby Starter Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/decoupled-drupal-gatsby-starter-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 17:10:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/decoupled-drupal-gatsby-starter-kit/</guid>
      <description>In doing the research that lead to my post about decoupled Drupal, I created a boilerplate project for using Gatsby with Drupal. The project is pretty basic but should have everything you need to get started. It uses docker-compose so you can run it anywhere you have docker installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coral Talk</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/coral-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/coral-talk/</guid>
      <description>When we moved a very high traffic client onto Kubernetes, we tried to split up their stack a bit.
The site is largely static, except for comments. So there was definitely an opportunity to save resources if we could spin off comments into a microservice decoupled from our main Drupal application.
We decided to use Coral Talk, and I spent quite a bit of time working on various custom plugins to fit our use-case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argo</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/argo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/argo/</guid>
      <description>When we made the switch to Kubernetes as a shop at Favish, we needed a way to ease onboarding everyone to the new stack.
Coming from the world of Vagrant where a pre-made virtual machine could be downloaded that included everything you needed, this tool was created in Golang to automatically install and configure things like Docker and kubectl for use with our clusters.
At the time, there were a few rough edges involved in interacting with the cluster to get things like database dumps and files into and out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squarereddit</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/squarereddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 17:42:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/squarereddit/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy having nice desktop backgrounds, and for awhile I was grabbing them from some subreddits for architecture and city-scapes. I decided to try out Angular and the Reddit API to make an easy to browse grid of images sourced from Reddit.
This project was primarily a way for me to experiment with Angular and as such I have not kept up with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallax Photos</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/parallax-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 17:40:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/parallax-photos/</guid>
      <description>The parrallax.js splash page is pretty awesome, so I decided to play with the library.
I cut up a few WW2 aircraft scenes and turned them into parrallax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Game Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/javascript-game-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 17:30:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/javascript-game-engine/</guid>
      <description>When I was starting to dig in to Javascript on my own, I was having a bit of a hard time getting my hands dirty in really large applications. I eventually found a (since removed) Udacity course on HTML5 Game Development which was produced by Google and walked students through building a game engine in JS.
The course was already quite dated when I found it. As a result, I needed to do quite a bit of self learning to fix up broken dependencies and patch old code bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MikaAguilar.com</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/mika-aguilar-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/mika-aguilar-com/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re lookin at it! I&amp;rsquo;ve been maintaining this site in it&amp;rsquo;s current repo since 2014. Before that, I had a pretty minimal portfolio hosted on my university&amp;rsquo;s website that began it&amp;rsquo;s life in 2006.
This is my personal playground, and I&amp;rsquo;m constantly iterating on it. It&amp;rsquo;s been on Angular, used a metric ton of Parallax, lived in Drupal, and a couple of other exploratory rewrites.
As of writing, I am using Hugo and GitHub Pages to build and host the site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>