<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Mika Aguilar</title>
    <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Mika Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 17:10:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupled Drupal with Gatsby Starter Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/decoupled-drupal-gatsby-starter-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 17:10:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/decoupled-drupal-gatsby-starter-kit/</guid>
      <description>In doing the research that lead to my post about decoupled Drupal, I created a boilerplate project for using Gatsby with Drupal. The project is pretty basic but should have everything you need to get started. It uses docker-compose so you can run it anywhere you have docker installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squarereddit</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/squarereddit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 17:42:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/squarereddit/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy having nice desktop backgrounds, and for awhile I was grabbing them from some subreddits for architecture and city-scapes. I decided to try out Angular and the Reddit API to make an easy to browse grid of images sourced from Reddit.
This project was primarily a way for me to experiment with Angular and as such I have not kept up with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallax Photos</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/parallax-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 17:40:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/parallax-photos/</guid>
      <description>The parrallax.js splash page is pretty awesome, so I decided to play with the library.
I cut up a few WW2 aircraft scenes and turned them into parrallax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Game Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/javascript-game-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 17:30:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mikaaguilar.com/projects/javascript-game-engine/</guid>
      <description>Long ago, I found Udacity&amp;rsquo;s cs255 course on building a game engine almost from scratch in JavaScript and had a go at it.
Everything except the physics engine is built with mostly vanilla javascript and minimal libraries. I did a fair bit of adjusting and fixing the engine to get it to work, which ended up being quite a bit of sort of reverse engineering because the course was mostly abandoned and the original game only sort of worked when I took the class.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>